<<<<<<< HEAD
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-08-17T20:03:48-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Just the F*cking Recipe</title><subtitle>I don't need your life story. I just want some food.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Burnt Orange Old Fashioned</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/19/old-fashioned" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Burnt Orange Old Fashioned" /><published>2021-08-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-08-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/08/19/old-fashioned</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/19/old-fashioned">&lt;p&gt;I just turned 39. Is that too young to be old fashioned? hyuk yuk yuk.
=======
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-08-17T18:03:21-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Just the F*cking Recipe</title><subtitle>I don't need your life story. I just want some food.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Burnt Orange Old Fashioned</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/19/old-fashioned" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Burnt Orange Old Fashioned" /><published>2021-08-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-08-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/08/19/old-fashioned</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/19/old-fashioned">&lt;p&gt;I just turned 39. Is that too young to be old fashioned? hyuk yuk yuk.
>>>>>>> a261341f162a209f58534093d7454ecda7ad04d9
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-you-need&quot;&gt;What you need:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some sort of fire producing apparatus, like a lighter or one of those fancy kitchen blowtorches&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A big chonky ice cube&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 oz rye or bourbon. I prefer bourbon because I like my throat to hurt.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 dashes orange bitters, or Angostura bitters if that’s what you have&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A rocks glass&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 slices of orange peel
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-this&quot;&gt;Do This:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add sugar, bitters, and water to the rocks glass and stir until sugar is mostly dissolved&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the chonky ice cube&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the booze and stir gently. It’s had a long day too, you know.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bend a slice of orange peel so the oils come out and rub on the rim of the glass&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;With your fire maker lit, bend the second slice and bring close to the flame to ignite the ccocktails&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drop the second slice in the glass&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drink responsibly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since there are a zillion ways to make an old fashioned, feel free to show me how wrong I am by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/aloria/aloria.github.io&quot;&gt;submitting your own&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/of.gif&quot; alt=&quot;old fashioned&quot; title=&quot;old fashioned&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>aloria</name></author><category term="ccocktails" /><summary type="html">I just turned 39. Is that too young to be old fashioned? hyuk yuk yuk.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tortilla Factory Salsa</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/19/salsa" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tortilla Factory Salsa" /><published>2021-08-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-08-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/08/19/salsa</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/19/salsa">&lt;p&gt;Submitted to us via email by Lizzie L, who seems like a really neat person. Lizzie describes this recipe as “an amazing salsa recipe from a now-closed tex-mex restaurant in Herndon, VA.”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-you-need&quot;&gt;What you need:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 29 oz. can crushed tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Medium onion, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 or more chopped cloves garlic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tbsp. crushed red pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tsp. Mexican oregano&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tsp. salt/to taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tbsp. ground black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4-6 oz. coarsely chopped cilantro&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2-3/4 cup red wine vinegar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 cup vegetable oil
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-this&quot;&gt;Do This:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blend all ingredients until smooth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Refrigerate for at least 8 hours (seriously it improves so much over time)
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mexican oregano is a completely different plant from standard oregano so try to get some if you can.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/salsa.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;salsa&quot; title=&quot;salsa&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Lizzie L</name></author><category term="condiments" /><category term="dips" /><summary type="html">Submitted to us via email by Lizzie L, who seems like a really neat person. Lizzie describes this recipe as “an amazing salsa recipe from a now-closed tex-mex restaurant in Herndon, VA.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Goulash. Pörkölt, actually: the real thing.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/18/goulash-the-real-thing" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Goulash. Pörkölt, actually: the real thing." /><published>2021-08-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-08-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/08/18/goulash-the-real-thing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/18/goulash-the-real-thing">&lt;p&gt;Learned if from my late (100 % Hungarian) grandma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t want my life story. But you do want to know which kind of meat to use, right? Bear with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gulyásleves&lt;/em&gt; is actually more of a soup than a stew. The stew itself is called &lt;em&gt;pörkölt&lt;/em&gt; and must consist of beef, onions, paprika, grease, and seasonings and maybe a tomato or two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The meat for a proper pörkölt is often cheap beef stew meat, the kind you simmer for hours and hours until it becomes nearly chewable. Not grandma. She always used „Nuß“, a part of the “head of the quadriceps” muscle, &lt;em&gt;musculus rectus femoris&lt;/em&gt;. It’s labelled „Zapfen“ in the image; just print the pretty picture and tell your butcher you want the part ringed in red. This is what the simmer time of 1.5 hours is calculated for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Wiener_Teilung_Zapfen.png&quot; alt=&quot;Beefiness&quot; title=&quot;Beefiness&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-you-need&quot;&gt;What you need&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For four really hungry people or eight normal eaters; more if you serve sides:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 kg (2.2 lbs.) beef, cubed to 15 mm (½”–¾”) a side.
Use good stew meat, see above.
Before cubing, strip the silvery-white sheath if present.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 kg white or yellow onions (same quantity as beef)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 large tomato;
or 2 medium ones;
or canned tomatoes or tomato paste (gross!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8 Tbsp paprika powder (sweet, and more helps more)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1.5 tsp paprika powder (spicy hot)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;abt. 150–200 g (5–7 oz.) pork lard (traditional);
or clarified butter;
or peanut or canola oils (meh) with a pat of butter for taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;preparation-is-easy-try-not-to-fuck-it-up&quot;&gt;Preparation is easy. Try not to fuck it up:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chop the onions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a large sauce pan, heat the fat and add the onions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stir on medium heat until the onions are transparent. Brown onions are bitter; discard and start over.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Extinguish with 2 or 3 Tbsp water.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add both paprika powders and allow the mixture to come to a boil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Extinguish with another 2–3 Tbsp water.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove and reserve most of the onions so that the beef can braise well.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the cubed beef and heat while stirring until the pores of the meat close; the surface will be grey-ish.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the reserved onions back in when the meat is braised.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the peeled and diced tomatoes and a good dose of salt.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add water until the meat is covered. If you need more than a pint or so per lb. of meat, use a smaller pot and reduce the sauce after cooking.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allow to simmer for 1.5 hours, stirring very occasionally. The result should be a watery sauce with delicious, tender meat cubes and discernible onion pieces.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Season to taste with more salt. If you want it spicier, add hot paprika; note that Hungarian cuisine is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; fiery-hot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above is what is known in Vienna as „Saftgulasch“ (“sauce-goulash”). Its distinguishing characteristic is that the sauce is bound only by the gelatin extracted from the meat during cooking, by the onion solids, and by reducing the stew to the desired consistency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, this dish is served with only dark rye bread on the side, but white bread will work, too, or rice, or Hungarian Tarhonya.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;variations-on-a-common-theme&quot;&gt;Variations on a common theme&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rindsgulasch, beef goulash.&lt;/strong&gt; Do not braise the beef in the onions. Instead, while the onions are cooking, cover the meat cubes in flour and sauté them in a separate pan. Then, add them to the onions and continue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zigeunergulasch, gypsy goulash.&lt;/strong&gt; Like Rindsgulasch in that the meat is floured and pan-browned. Uses beef, lamb, or pork, or any mix of these. Later in the cooking, add diced potatoes, diced green bell peppers, and diced tomato (in addition to the tomato you already used).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Esterházygulasch.&lt;/strong&gt; Named after the blue-blood Esterházy family. Prepare a Rindsgulasch, bind with sour cream, add a julienne of yellow beets, carrots, and celery root; refine with more sour cream, and serve with Salzkartoffeln (salt potatoes: put raw peeled potatoes in heavily salted cold water, bring to boil, simmer for ~20 minutes until done, pour off water, let stand for two minutes, add chopped dill or chopped flat parsley if desired).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Karlsbader Gulasch.&lt;/strong&gt; So named after the spa resort for the rich in the old Austrian monarchy. Prepare a basic goulash; stir some flour into cold water (no clumping, please!), add sour cream generously, stir into the goulash. Serve with Nockerln (Italian potato gnocchi will do in a pinch).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kaisergulasch, Emperor goulash.&lt;/strong&gt; Use beef tenderloin and adjust cooking time. Serve with “lard-noodles” („abgeschmalzene Nudeln“): cook egg noodles, like German-style „Spätzle“ or what you find at the Asian grocery, until soft. Meanwhile, finely chop an onion and fry it in lard until transparent, then continue frying until it is yellow. Pour over the pasta and serve. Alternative: instead of lard, render diced bacon and use that to fry the chopped onion. Yum!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bauerngulasch, peasant’s goulash.&lt;/strong&gt; Rindsgulasch as above, garnished with small Semmelknödel (I have a recipe for that, too).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fiakergulasch, coachman’s goulash, Herrengulasch, gentleman’s goulash.&lt;/strong&gt; Rindsgulasch garnished with a pan-fried egg (traditionally sunny side up), a pan-fried Frankfurter or two, a partially sliced and spread into fan-shape gherkin (cornichon may be substituted). Optional: A couple of slices of Semmelknödel, maybe even pan-fried; otherwise white bread.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>felixk</name></author><category term="meats" /><summary type="html">Learned if from my late (100 % Hungarian) grandma. You don’t want my life story. But you do want to know which kind of meat to use, right? Bear with me. Gulyásleves is actually more of a soup than a stew. The stew itself is called pörkölt and must consist of beef, onions, paprika, grease, and seasonings and maybe a tomato or two. The meat for a proper pörkölt is often cheap beef stew meat, the kind you simmer for hours and hours until it becomes nearly chewable. Not grandma. She always used „Nuß“, a part of the “head of the quadriceps” muscle, musculus rectus femoris. It’s labelled „Zapfen“ in the image; just print the pretty picture and tell your butcher you want the part ringed in red. This is what the simmer time of 1.5 hours is calculated for. What you need For four really hungry people or eight normal eaters; more if you serve sides: 1 kg (2.2 lbs.) beef, cubed to 15 mm (½”–¾”) a side. Use good stew meat, see above. Before cubing, strip the silvery-white sheath if present. 1 kg white or yellow onions (same quantity as beef) 1 large tomato; or 2 medium ones; or canned tomatoes or tomato paste (gross!) 8 Tbsp paprika powder (sweet, and more helps more) 1.5 tsp paprika powder (spicy hot) abt. 150–200 g (5–7 oz.) pork lard (traditional); or clarified butter; or peanut or canola oils (meh) with a pat of butter for taste Salt Water Preparation is easy. Try not to fuck it up: Chop the onions. In a large sauce pan, heat the fat and add the onions. Stir on medium heat until the onions are transparent. Brown onions are bitter; discard and start over. Extinguish with 2 or 3 Tbsp water. Add both paprika powders and allow the mixture to come to a boil Extinguish with another 2–3 Tbsp water. Remove and reserve most of the onions so that the beef can braise well. Add the cubed beef and heat while stirring until the pores of the meat close; the surface will be grey-ish. Add the reserved onions back in when the meat is braised. Add the peeled and diced tomatoes and a good dose of salt. Add water until the meat is covered. If you need more than a pint or so per lb. of meat, use a smaller pot and reduce the sauce after cooking. Allow to simmer for 1.5 hours, stirring very occasionally. The result should be a watery sauce with delicious, tender meat cubes and discernible onion pieces. Season to taste with more salt. If you want it spicier, add hot paprika; note that Hungarian cuisine is not fiery-hot. The above is what is known in Vienna as „Saftgulasch“ (“sauce-goulash”). Its distinguishing characteristic is that the sauce is bound only by the gelatin extracted from the meat during cooking, by the onion solids, and by reducing the stew to the desired consistency. Traditionally, this dish is served with only dark rye bread on the side, but white bread will work, too, or rice, or Hungarian Tarhonya. Variations on a common theme Rindsgulasch, beef goulash. Do not braise the beef in the onions. Instead, while the onions are cooking, cover the meat cubes in flour and sauté them in a separate pan. Then, add them to the onions and continue. Zigeunergulasch, gypsy goulash. Like Rindsgulasch in that the meat is floured and pan-browned. Uses beef, lamb, or pork, or any mix of these. Later in the cooking, add diced potatoes, diced green bell peppers, and diced tomato (in addition to the tomato you already used). Esterházygulasch. Named after the blue-blood Esterházy family. Prepare a Rindsgulasch, bind with sour cream, add a julienne of yellow beets, carrots, and celery root; refine with more sour cream, and serve with Salzkartoffeln (salt potatoes: put raw peeled potatoes in heavily salted cold water, bring to boil, simmer for ~20 minutes until done, pour off water, let stand for two minutes, add chopped dill or chopped flat parsley if desired). Karlsbader Gulasch. So named after the spa resort for the rich in the old Austrian monarchy. Prepare a basic goulash; stir some flour into cold water (no clumping, please!), add sour cream generously, stir into the goulash. Serve with Nockerln (Italian potato gnocchi will do in a pinch). Kaisergulasch, Emperor goulash. Use beef tenderloin and adjust cooking time. Serve with “lard-noodles” („abgeschmalzene Nudeln“): cook egg noodles, like German-style „Spätzle“ or what you find at the Asian grocery, until soft. Meanwhile, finely chop an onion and fry it in lard until transparent, then continue frying until it is yellow. Pour over the pasta and serve. Alternative: instead of lard, render diced bacon and use that to fry the chopped onion. Yum! Bauerngulasch, peasant’s goulash. Rindsgulasch as above, garnished with small Semmelknödel (I have a recipe for that, too). Fiakergulasch, coachman’s goulash, Herrengulasch, gentleman’s goulash. Rindsgulasch garnished with a pan-fried egg (traditionally sunny side up), a pan-fried Frankfurter or two, a partially sliced and spread into fan-shape gherkin (cornichon may be substituted). Optional: A couple of slices of Semmelknödel, maybe even pan-fried; otherwise white bread.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">French Dressing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/17/french-dressing" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="French Dressing" /><published>2021-08-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-08-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/08/17/french-dressing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/17/french-dressing">&lt;p&gt;Another hit by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mramblr&quot;&gt;Midnight Rambler&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-you-need&quot;&gt;What you need&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 cup red wine vinegar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;balsamic vinegar to bring up to 1/3 cup&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 1/2 tsp salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ground black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp Dijon mustard&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 cloves garlic, crushed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;tiny pinch sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-this&quot;&gt;Do this&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mix together in order, making sure the salt is completely dissolved before adding the mustard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 cup olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 cup canola, grapeseed, or other vegetable oil*&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blend with a hand blender so it’s smooth and emulsified.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the proportions are right, it should hardly separate at all even after days. Add a little more oil if needed to get the flavor balance right (after trying it on salad).
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/french.gif&quot; alt=&quot;french&quot; title=&quot;french&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Midnight Rambler</name></author><category term="condiments" /><summary type="html">Another hit by Midnight Rambler.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Vegetable Pie with Chicken</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/16/veg-pie" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Vegetable Pie with Chicken" /><published>2021-08-16T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-08-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/08/16/veg-pie</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/16/veg-pie">&lt;p&gt;Submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;https://liadan.wordpress.com/2010/12/21/vegitable-pie-with-chicken/&quot;&gt;liadan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-you-need&quot;&gt;What you need&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Olive Oil (Extra Virgin)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Onion Powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Garlic Powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sweet Basil Crushed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ground Pepper&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the crust:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 medium zucchini, shredded&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup mozzarella, shredded&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup pepper jack, shredded&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 eggs&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the topping:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pat the zucchini dry and mix with cheese&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beat the eggs and mix with zucchini/cheese mixture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add in about 2 tsp Salt and 1 TBSP pepper and mix well&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add garlic powder and onion powder to taste (I like about 1 tsp each)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cook in oven at 400°F for 10 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove and pat excess moisture off
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; You can generally cook everything that goes on top of the zucchini crust while the crust bakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-this&quot;&gt;Do this&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sauté the pepper in ~1 tsp of olive oil (Just enough to barely cover the bottom of a 5 inch pan)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cook until tender and starting to brown then set aside in a bowl&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cook green onion in ~1 tsp of olive oil season with large pinch of onion powder and garlic powder.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once the onion starts becoming translucent, add mushroom and cook until they start softening but before they start to sweat.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Set aside in a bowl.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a large pan (~10 inches) put in about 2 tsp of olive oil (enough to cover bottom barely)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sautė the Chicken with 2 pinches of garlic powder and 2 pinches of onion powder. Add sweet basil about 1 pinch&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; You want the chicken to be cooked white on the outside and almost fully cooked inside but not dry and not completely finished.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once the zucchini crust comes out of the oven and has been patted dry, add the peppers, mushroom and onions, then the tomato and chicken.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cover with cheese &amp;amp; basil across the top so that it covers all the cheese on top and place in the oven again for 25 minutes at 400°F.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can get about 8 small servings or 4 large servings out of this.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pie.gif&quot; alt=&quot;pie&quot; title=&quot;pie&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>liadan</name></author><category term="meats" /><category term="baked" /><summary type="html">Submitted by liadan.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Spam Musubi</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/15/spam-musubi" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Spam Musubi" /><published>2021-08-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-08-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/08/15/spam-musubi</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/15/spam-musubi">&lt;p&gt;Graciously brought to us by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mramblr&quot;&gt;Midnight Rambler&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-you-need&quot;&gt;What you need&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 can spam&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 cups short-grain Japanese style rice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 sheets nori&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;optional: 1 tsp sugar, 1-2 tbsp rice vinegar, jelly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-this&quot;&gt;Do this&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rinse the rice and cook with salt beforehand.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add sugar and vinegar to cooked rice while hot if desired.  Let cool to at least lukewarm.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slice spam into 8 equal slices (parallel to top of can) and saute until lightly browned on each side.  Don’t let it get crispy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Near the end, toss in some jelly (guava is good) and/or soy sauce and cook into the spam.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cut the bottom out of the spam can with a can opener.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cut the nori in half, so that each half is about as long as a piece of spam.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To assemble, put the can over the middle of a piece of nori, put a slice of spam in, add about 1 inch of rice, pack down, remove can, and tightly wrap nori around, moistening the ends to seal.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; you can also use a musubi press instead of the can and a wire meat slicer. But usually those are for 10 slices which IMO is too thin and in the other direction, which isn’t optimized for the nori sheets. YMMV.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/spam.gif&quot; alt=&quot;spam&quot; title=&quot;spam&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Midnight Rambler</name></author><category term="meats" /><category term="carbs" /><summary type="html">Graciously brought to us by Midnight Rambler.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chipped Ham on Toast</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/01/chipped-ham-on-toast" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chipped Ham on Toast" /><published>2021-08-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-08-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/08/01/chipped-ham-on-toast</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/01/chipped-ham-on-toast">&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-you-need&quot;&gt;What you need&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Medium saucepan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whisk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tbsp butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 clove of garlic, diced, pressed or smooshed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tbsp flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;salt &amp;amp; pepper, to taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup milk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup of deli sliced ham, cut into strips or squares&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 slices of bread, toasted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-this&quot;&gt;Do this&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Melt the butter in a saucepan.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Put garlic in and cook until fragrant, only a minute or two.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sprinkle in flour, salt and pepper, whisk until it forms a paste.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stir in milk, whisking constantly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cook over medium heat until mixture boils and thickens a little, still whisking constantly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove from heat. Add ham to the sauce and heat through.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Serve over toast.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
You may prefer more meat, or less meat depending on how much sauce you have. YMMV.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="meats" /><category term="breakfast" /><summary type="html">What you need Medium saucepan Whisk 2 tbsp butter 1 clove of garlic, diced, pressed or smooshed. 2 tbsp flour salt &amp;amp; pepper, to taste 1 cup milk 1 cup of deli sliced ham, cut into strips or squares 2 slices of bread, toasted</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sweet Potato Casserole</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/07/09/sweet-potato-casserole" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sweet Potato Casserole" /><published>2021-07-09T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-07-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/07/09/sweet-potato-casserole</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/07/09/sweet-potato-casserole">&lt;p&gt;By &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/archwisp&quot;&gt;@archwisp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-you-need&quot;&gt;What you need&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 cups mashed sweet potatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tbsp vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 stick butter or margarine&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 eggs
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
For the topping:&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/3 cups flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/3 cup butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup chopped pecans
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-this&quot;&gt;Do this&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 325 °F&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mix potatoes, sugar, eggs, and vanilla together. Spread mixture into a casserole dish&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a new bowl, cut butter into flour and brown sugar and mix until crumbly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spread over potatoes. Sprinkle chopped pecans on top&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake for 30 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; this can be made ahead of time and frozen, or made in 2 separate casserole dishes
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/potat.gif&quot; alt=&quot;potat&quot; title=&quot;potat&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>archwisp</name></author><category term="sides" /><category term="casseroles" /><summary type="html">By @archwisp.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Balsamic Chicken</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/07/08/balsamic-chicken" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Balsamic Chicken" /><published>2021-07-08T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-07-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/07/08/balsamic-chicken</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/07/08/balsamic-chicken">&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-you-need&quot;&gt;What you need&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 chicken breasts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 cloves minced garlic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;.5 cup balsamic vinegar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;.25 tsp oregano&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;.25 tsp parsley&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;.25 tsp garlic powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tbsp sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;.25 tsp red chili flakes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;0.25 cups chicken broth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tbsp olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-this&quot;&gt;Do this&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a container, mix broth, vinegar, sugar and spices&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add chicken breasts and give it a good shake. Marinate overnight&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heat oil in a pan on medium-high heat&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove chicken from marinate and cook ~7 minutes on each side&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add marinade to pan and cook until thickened, turning the chicken over periodically for ~5 minutes
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sh.gif&quot; alt=&quot;sledgehammer&quot; title=&quot;sledgehammer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>aloria</name></author><category term="meats" /><summary type="html">What you need 4 chicken breasts 2 cloves minced garlic .5 cup balsamic vinegar .25 tsp oregano .25 tsp parsley .25 tsp garlic powder 2 tbsp sugar .25 tsp red chili flakes 0.25 cups chicken broth 1 tbsp olive oil</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Guacamole</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/07/07/guac" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guacamole" /><published>2021-07-07T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-07-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/07/07/guac</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/07/07/guac">&lt;p&gt;By &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/archwisp&quot;&gt;@archwisp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-you-need&quot;&gt;What you need&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 ripe avocadoes, seeded&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp ground cumin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;.5 cup minced sweet white onion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 serrano chiles, seeded and minced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;.25 cup chopped cilantro&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tbsp lime juice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(to taste) hot pepper sauce, sea salt, white pepper
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-this&quot;&gt;Do this&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cut avocado into large chunks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a large bowl, coarsely mash avocado and cilantro with a fork&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add remaining ingredients and mix gently&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Season to taste
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/guac.gif&quot; alt=&quot;guac&quot; title=&quot;guac&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>archwisp</name></author><category term="condiments" /><category term="dips" /><summary type="html">By @archwisp.</summary></entry></feed>